<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on arner</title><link>https://arner.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on arner</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 22:05:18 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://arner.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install the oucher</title><link>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 22:05:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-3/</guid><description>This post is part of a series.
Do you want to make GLaDOS clean your floor? Have you rooted your Xiaomi or Roborock vacuum cleaner? Have you installed the GLaDOS voice pack? Do you want to make her say stuff when she bumps into something?
Good, let&amp;rsquo;s continue.
A vacuum robot that verbally reacts when it bumps into things is surprisingly funny.
It&amp;rsquo;s also a good way to add a bit more personality to a robot that already has a voice pack installed.</description></item><item><title>Install the GLaDOS voice pack</title><link>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 21:42:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-2/</guid><description>This post is part of a series.
Do you want to make GLaDOS clean your floor? Have you rooted your Xiaomi or Roborock vacuum cleaner? Good. Let&amp;rsquo;s continue.
The lazy version of this is actually really simple.
The lazy version Download the GLaDOS voice pack here and unzip it. Visit Valetudo in your browser (the IP of your vacuum) and go to Settings -&amp;gt; Sound and voice. Upload the downloaded .</description></item><item><title>Root your Xiaomi vacuum</title><link>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 19:45:24 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-1/</guid><description>This guide describes how to root your Xiaomi/Roborock vacuum (meaning to gain administrator access). Check here if it works on yours.
The standard firmware requires a connection to the internet and it transmits information about your wifi SSID, gateway mac address and other information like your floor plan to Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s servers every thirty minutes. If this makes you feel a bit uncomfortable, good, read on.
Rooting changes your vacuum cleaner from an appliance that needs the Chinese cloud to function to a computer that you own and control via your local wifi directly.</description></item><item><title>Make GLaDOS clean your floor</title><link>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 17:13:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://arner.github.io/posts/glados-0/</guid><description>Since last weekend my floor is cleaned by GLaDOS, the artificial intelligence who supervises the Aperture Science testing facilities in the Portal games.
Watch this video to get an idea of her delightful personality. Buy the games on Steam if you haven&amp;rsquo;t played them yet, they&amp;rsquo;re awesome!
In this series of blog posts I&amp;rsquo;ll document how I got her to perform the simple task of cleaning my floor - albeit somewhat reluctantly.</description></item></channel></rss>